Article Inwara

https://www.inwara.com/report/blockchain-crypto-report-h1-2019  https://www.inwara.com/images/h1_2019_report/imgonline-com-ua-twotoone-Fjz2uO4OmBPKvL.png https://www.inwara.com/images/h1_2019_report/imgonline-com-ua-twotoone-ApmOU7pGCx.png 
 01 July 2019	
 Executive Summary of InWara’s Half-Yearly report — H1 2019 
Following an underwhelming H2 2018 for the Blockchain and crypto market, 2019 has sparked renewed interest because of — a new blockchain-based investment vehicle dubbed IEOs, better jurisdictional clarification of digital assets, and also the entry of established enterprises like Facebook and JPMorgan.
The largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization, Bitcoin, has regained more than 200% of its spot trading price and overall the market has gained more than 155%, signalling the end of the metaphorical ‘crypto winter’ — Perhaps, Spring wasn’t that far behind!
Here are the Key Takeaways from the report -
Despite the crypto winter being over why are professional investors showing lacklustre interest? A plausible reason could be the current technological limitations of existing Blockchain technology which has still yet to provide scalable enterprise solutions.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------


https://www.inwara.com/inwara-news/280-decentralized-media-platform-refine-launches-its-ico  https://www.inwara.com/images/123images/001may7.png 
 29 June 2019	
 Decentralized media platform — Refine Medium launches its ICO 
We all consume content on a regular basis, be it print or digital form but something we don’t often think about is how these media channels are making money. Hong Kong-based media company — Refine Medium, aims to pivot from traditional media platforms by creating a truly decentralized media platform that is powered by Blockchain technology.
In order to develop such a platform, the company has started a fundraising program by launching its Pre-sale Initial Coin Offering (ICO) on 25th June, according to InWara’s Market Intelligence Platform. 
Blockchain and crypto startups have gradually branched out to off-beat industry sectors like Media and Entertainment from initially being to a handful of sectors like Financial Services, Trading and Investing, and Fintech. Maybe it’s because the first blockchain powered product Bitcoin is a peer-to-peer payments platform, which showed demonstrated the potential in the Financial ecosystem.
InWara's Monthly Report: May 2019
Media and entertainment startups raised as much as $132.5 million during the month of May alone, based on our report. But this is still a relatively amount number when compared to the ~$1.2 billion raised by Fintech startups and ~$1 billion raised by Trading and Investing startups.
So even though it’s been 10 years since the inception of Blockchain technology, investors are still keen on backing startups in the Financial ecosystem. It’s important to note that these startups are usually not building Blockchain infrastructure instead, is leveraging existing Blockchain technology
So what’s Refine Medium’s vision?
The company intends to create a unique digital ecosystem that according to the company white paper aims to “bridge the gap between “human being” & “being human” as humanity thrives forever”. 
The problem with current media platforms is that the ‘wealth distribution’ isn’t fair. Take Youtube, for example, Google makes a lot of money on Ads, the content creators make some money ( although just a fraction of what Google makes) and content consumers gain nothing. 
Refine Medium like many other Blockchain powered media companies is proposing to change this format by enabling content consumers to earn money for spending time on their platform — a great incentive for people to shift to these platforms.a

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------


https://www.inwara.com/dayta-launches-ieo-on-latoken  https://www.inwara.com/images/123images/001may2.png 
 28 June 2019	
 Dayta launches its Initial Exchange Offering (IEO) on LATOKEN’s platform 
UK-based data management platform — Dayta, that lets users leverage their personal data for monetary benefits is all set to launch its Initial Exchange Offering (IEO) on LATOKEN’s IEO platform on June 28th, according to our Market Intelligence Platform.
Dayta’s vision for its future
Firstly, what’s Dayto? It’s a platform designed to a 360-degree data management ecosystem. The company aims to solve multiple issues inherently present in our digital age where data privacy and management is often violated. 
You’ve probably heard of numerous data scandals like Cambridge Analytica, Equifax, and Marriot where the personal data of hundreds of millions of users (not an exaggeration) were leaked? Dayto aimed to prevent future scandals like this by leveraging Blockchain technology. 
But that’s not the highlight, the company actually promotes its users to profit from their personal data by willingly sharing it with corporate clients and advertisers.
The conundrum of Initial Exchange Offerings
Notably, LATOKEN is one of the most popular IEO platform’s right now and has raised over $100 million on its IEO platform.
InWara’s Initial Exchange Offering report
While publishing our IEO report as many as 21 IEO projects have been launched on LATOKEN’s platform, a staggering number considering its infancy. For comparison, Binance who is considered to be the pioneer in IEO space has only launched 7 projects so far.
But sheer numbers are not everything, quality matters too. For example, Gate.io has only launched 3 IEO projects but these three projects managed to raise a whopping $290 million. In light of this, there are numerous concerns about the quality of IEO projects being launched and with good reason. 
Some exchanges like Binance have strict vetting processes in place purportedly, you can expect that level of quality from the world’s largest crypto exchange. But can you really expect that level of authenticity from the smaller exchanges? Especially when there’s a monetary incentive for them. And this is why some people are crying wolf because, without a universal vetting process, you can’t compare the quality of two IEO projects. For more information on Dayta IEO check out InWara’s weekly roundup of blockchain and crypto projects

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------


https://www.inwara.com/collinstar-invests-in-social-media-platform-tictalk  
 27 June 2019	
 Collinstar Capital invests undisclosed amount in Blockchain-based social media platform — TicTalk 
TicTalk is a novel Blockchain based social media platform based out of China, whose name is eerily similar to the widely popular social media platform from China. But the key differentiator here is that TicTalk is purportedly a Blockchain-powered platform that offers some novel features such as people-oriented navigation and search. 
TicTalk recently raised an undisclosed amount in Seed funding from industry leading Venture Capital firm CollinStar Capital, according to InWara’s Market Intelligence Platform.
This deal marks the first time CollinStar Capital has invested in Social Media industry sector.

InWara’s Market Intelligence Platform
Collinstar Capital has previously invested in several startups which are a part of the broader Blockchain ecosystem. We’ll be focusing just on these investments. As much as 80% of these startups were focused purely on advancing Blockchain technology or inventing new Blockchain infrastructure. These are businesses that offer novel technology as their product/ service.
The remaining 20% of these startups belong to the Financial Services industry sector, meaning these are startups that are leveraging Blockchain technology to offer a product/service in the broader Financial ecosystem. It’s important to note that these startups are usually using already existing Blockchain platforms like Ethereum, Waves, etc and not building their own Blockchain infrastructure.
So what’s TicTalk’s vision?
The Chinese company aims to be a distributed digital identification platform on top of being just a social media company. Also, the TicTalk foundation believes the new platform will integrate well into its larger Vecahin ecosystem. With ambitious aims of creating a global platform that gives priority to free will, individual value, privacy among other liberal views — the extent to which these ideals, are executable in real-life, is still unknown since this company hails from China. 
But the end goal for TicTalk’s ecosystem can be divided into three parts — front, middle, and Investment. Projects which match the current need of users on TicTalk’s platform like TicTalk voting, dating, etc all fall under front-end. This is not to be confused with web developer Jargon. In the middle-end, we have services including operations, technology, products, and marketing. And finally, investment includes seed-stage funding, angel-stage funding and crowdfunding — which is taking place right now,

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------


https://www.inwara.com/decentralized-trading-platform-marketc-launches-ieo  https://www.inwara.com/images/123images/001may4.png https://www.inwara.com/images/pasted_image_031.png 
 27 June 2019	
 Decentralized trading platform — MarketC has launched its IEO on p2pb2b 
Based out of Germany, MarketC is a blockchain-based digital platform that aims to tackle the problems with Foreign exchange (Forex) trading by providing a decentralized trading which is secure and low-cost. On June 24th, the company has launched its Initial Exchange Offering (IEO) on p2pb2b exchange with each CMk token priced at $0.3 and a Mainsale Hardcap of $2.7 million, according to InWara’s Market Intelligence Platform.
Is $2.7 million an ambitious target? Let’s compare the data.
InWara’s monthly report: May 2019
During the month of May alone, Blockchain and crypto projects managed to raise a whopping $2.65 billion — IEO projects raised $1.2 billion (45%), STO projects raised $265 million and ICO projects raised $105 million. Also, just over $1 billion was raised through traditional Venture capital funding
Clearly, IEO projects outperformed every other fundraising model during last month with the closest competition in the fundraising space being STOs.
Founded by Abner Smit and Ambrose Barleti way back in 2017, the company has come a long way since then. In 2018, the company expanded quite rapidly by first opening up partnership offices with Google and Facebook in Russia, then expanding to Asian markets like Thailand, India, and the Philippines.
This year, MarketC has planned to establish its trading platform by obtaining licenses, Market. Finance digital wallet launch and market.Trade crypto exchange launch. Its crypto exchange will be a core element of MarketC’s business model as is expected to roll out by December 2019.
InWara’s Market Intelligence Platform
By the end of Q1 2020, MarketC expects to launch a mobile version of its trading platform Market.Trade and is likely to be made available to Android and iOS app store. Interestingly, the company aims to pivot or maybe add from its current business model by launching a market news portal dubbed market.News.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------


https://www.inwara.com/decentralized-trading-platform-bankdex-launches-ico  https://www.inwara.com/images/MVP_211.png 
 27 June 2019	
 Decentralized trading platform — Bankdex has launched its ICO 
Bankdex is a Hong Kong-based decentralized trading platform (exchange) for cryptocurrencies that was founded by Reza Solgi, Abdolreza Alameri, Hamed Reza Alameri, and Mohammad Solgi.
On June 24th, BankDex has launched its pre-sale Initial Coin Offering (ICO), according to our Market Intelligence Platform. As many as 1 billion SAM tokens will be issued by the company, out of which 450 million will be available for purchase to investors. 1 SAM token will be worth $0.019 and a 25% bonus during the Pre Sale event. 
But aren’t there already 300+ crypto exchanges in the world already? Of which only a few dozen are running a profitable business, so why launch another one? 
Unlike traditional crypto exchanges, Bankdex is among a new breed of trading platforms that leverages a new blockchain infrastructure to enable direct peer-to-peer trading — if you haven’t guessed from the name yet, Bankdex is a decentralized exchange.
But quite embarrassingly, the link to see the Minimum Viable Product (MVP) on Bankdex’s official ICO website doesn’t seem to be working as of writing this article. So there’s no definitive way to know what’s the actual progress of the platform. 
So why is it important to have an MVP?
From our research based on the extensive of 5500 Initial Coin Offering projects available on our platform, we were able to find out that only 26% of these projects possessed an MVP during the time of their token sale. 
But what’s even more shocking is the correlation between the failure of ICO projects and possessing an MVP.
source
It’s no news that ICO projects are prone to failure — here failure means shutting down as a business, founders or management unresponsive while leaving investors in the dust and over the last few years hundreds of ICO projects have failed. 
But what’s surprising is the correlation between the presence of an MVP and the failure of ICO projects. As much as 95% of failed companies did not possess an MVP during the launch of their token sale. 
So why is this so? In our research of thousands of Blockchain and crypto companies, we’ve noticed something. A startup adds value to the world by solving an existing problem through its product/ service but in the Blockchain and crypto space — blockchain technology is treated as a panacea for all problems without stopping to think “ Is this solution the best way to solve this problem?” 
To know more about why ICO fails, Check out our ICO research article.

---------------------------------------------------------------------------------

